So, now we have reason to believe that something has
现在我们有理由认为
changed about the underlying distribution of the data.
数据的底层分布发生了变化
Our proposed solution is to train
建议的解决方案是
a new model on the new data and replace the original model.
用新数据训练新的模型并替换旧模型
To start, we need to make sure that we create a valid training set.
首先 我们需要创建有效的训练集
So, earlier, we used the new reviews to create a new vocabulary.
之前 我们使用新影评创建了新的词汇表
Now, we need to use that new vocabulary to create
现在需要使用新词汇表
a bag of words encoding of our new data.
创建表示新数据的词袋
Once this is done, as a quick check,
操作完毕后 快速检查下
we should make sure that the size of any row in our new bag
看看用新词袋编码的数据集的大小
of words encoded data set is equal to the length of the vocabulary that we were using.
是否等于要使用的词汇表的长度
In this case, our vocabulary has the length of 5,000,
我们的词汇表长度为 5,000
and so we should expect the length of each row to also be 5,000, which it is.
所以每行的长度应该为 5,000 的确是
Once that's done, we need to split our new data into a training and validation set,
检查完毕后 我们需要将新数据拆分成训练集和验证集
so that we can save our new data along with
并将新数据以及新训练集和验证集
the new training and validation sets to our local instance.
保存到本地实例中
Once that's done, we upload all of the data to s3 using the upload data method,
然后 使用 upload_data 方法将所有数据上传到 S3
so that we can create and train a new XGBoost model.
从而创建和训练新的 XGBoost 模型
We begin by setting up an estimator.
首先设置一个 estimator 对象
In this case, I've used
这里使用的超参数
the same hyperparameters as we used in the original XGBoost model.
与原始 XGBoost 模型的超参数一样
Once we've created the estimator object,
创建 estimator 对象后
we can then call the fit method and fit our new XGBoost model to the new data set.
调用 fit() 方法并用新的 XGBoost 模型拟合新数据集
So, now we should probably make sure that
下面看看新模型
our new model is behaving in a way that we expect.
是否能达到预期行为
One of the first ways we will do that is by
一般 我们首先会
testing our new model on the data that we use to train it.
用训练模型的数据测试新模型
In practice, this is a pretty bad idea.
实际上这种做法不可取
Since we use the new data to train the model,
因为我们使用了新数据训练模型
testing it on that same data is a textbook example of leakage,
使用相同的数据测试模型属于典型的数据泄露问题
and you should never do this in a real application.
在实际操作中千万不要犯这种错误
In our case, the reason we're doing it is so that we
我们这么测试只是为了
have a numerical baseline to compare things too.
有一个数值基准可以进行比较
So, in order to test our new model,
为了测试新模型
we create a new transformer object,
我们将创建新的 transformer 对象
which we use to create a transform job on our new data.
并用该对象创建一个转换作业用在新数据上
Once that transform job has finished,
转换作业运行完毕后
we copy the results to our local instance and check to see how well it's doing.
将结果复制到本地实例上 并看看模型的表现
Seems like our new model is behaving pretty well on the new data.
看来新模型在新数据上的表现很好
Of course, we expect this to be true since our new model was trained on that same data.
肯定很好 因为新模型是用相同的数据训练的
A second thing we're going to check is that our model is
还要检查的是
behaving okay relative to the old data.
模型在旧数据上是否也相对不错
We don't expect that the distribution has changed so much
我们不希望数据分布已经明显改变
that our new model should behave very poorly on old data.
导致新模型在旧数据上的表现很糟糕
So, we start by reading in the original test data and then transforming it.
首先读取原始测试集 然后转换它
The reason for doing this is that we are using a new vocabulary for our new model,
因为新模型使用的是新词汇表
and so we need to make sure that when we create a bag
所以在用词袋
of words encoding of the original test set,
编码原始测试集时
we use the new vocabulary to do it.
我们将使用新词汇表
Using the new_vectorizer that we constructed earlier,
使用之前创建的 new_vectorizer
we can transform the original test set into a bag of words encoded version.
将原始测试集转换成词袋版本
Once we've done that, we can write the results to our local instance,
然后 将结果写入本地实例中
upload that file to s3,
并将文件上传到 S3 上
and then transform it using our new model.
然后使用新模型转换它
Once that's done, we can check to see how well our model is
看看模型的效果如何
doing and it seems like it's doing not so bad.
似乎并不糟糕
So, in general, it would appear that
看来新的 XGBoost 模型
our new XGBoost model is doing exactly what we wanted to.
行为完全符合我们的预期
It's performing well on the new data and is performing well on the old data.
它在新数据和旧数据上的表现都不错
It seems like it would be a good idea to switch
似乎可以将现有端点
our existing endpoint to using the new model.
切换为使用新的模型
Of course, since we are imagining that we have
因为我们假设有一个
some application running using the original model,
使用原始模型的应用正在运行
we should make sure that we use sagemakers update functionality,
所以需要使用 SageMaker 的更新功能
so that our endpoint never has to get shut down.
这样的话 端点就不会关闭
Recall that in order to update an endpoint,
为了更新端点
we need to create a new endpoint configuration.
我们需要创建新的端点配置
In order to create an endpoint configuration,
为了创建端点配置
we need to know the name of the model we'd like to send our data to.
我们需要知道要向其发送数据的模型的名称
We can get that name from the transformer object that we created earlier.
我们可以从之前创建的 transformer 对象中获取该名称
Once we've got the model name,
获得模型名称后
we can then create a new endpoint configuration.
我们可以创建一个新的端点配置
In this case, we're creating
我们创建的端点配置
an endpoint configuration which has only a single production variant,
只有一个生产变体
which is our new XGBoost model.
即新的 XGBoost 模型
Once that endpoint configuration has been created,
创建了端点配置后
we can ask sagemaker to update our existing endpoint,
我们可以要求 SageMaker 更新现有端点
so that its new configuration uses the new XGBoost model.
使其新配置使用新的 XGBoost 模型
Now, in our real life scenario,
在现实中
this would be a job well done.
这项工作已经完成的很好
We have diagnosed the problem,
我们诊断出问题
created a solution to that problem,
创建了问题解决方案
and then updated our endpoint such that our end user didn't experience any loss of usage.
然后更新了端点 并且最终用户不会体验到服务中断现象
Since we no longer need the endpoint that is deployed,
因为我们不再需要这个部署端点
we should make sure to delete it.
所以应该删除该端点
I'd also like to point out that there are some additional questions here at the end,
最后 我还要指出几个其他问题
and these questions are really meant to be open-ended.
这些问题并没有什么标准答案
For example, what other ways could the underlying distribution
例如 如果我们要尝试创建情感分析模型
possibly change if we were trying to create a sentiment analysis model?
底层分布还会有哪些改变
This might be useful in more applications than just
这个问题在应用中的用处更大
determining whether or not a movie review is positive or negative.
而不仅仅是判断影评是正面的还是负面的
For example, in some cases,
例如 在某些情形下
firms use sentiment analysis of
企业会根据股东的
shareholder reports to determine whether or
情感分析报告
not a stock is going to perform well or poorly.
判断某支股票表现不错还是表现很差
Another question is, since we didn't want our model
还有一个问题 因为我们不希望新模型
to change too significantly from the original model,
与原始模型的差别很大
was it a good idea to train the new model using only the new data?
那么仅使用新数据训练模型合适吗？
Should we have instead mixed the data in some way?
应该以某种方式混合数据吗？
If so, in what proportion should we mix it?
如果应该混合 混合比例是多少？
Lastly, in this example,
最后 在本示例中
the new data that we received was quite significant,
我们收到了大量新数据
so we could use it to train our model.
足以用来训练模型
But what if you had much fewer examples?
但是如果样本量少多了呢？
Suppose that you were given a new data set that only had 500 samples.
假设新数据集只有 500 个样本
Not really enough to create a new model,
不足以创建新的模型
but enough to know that your old model wasn't behaving very well.
但是足以知道旧模型表现不佳
How would you fix that? As I said earlier,
如何解决该问题？正如我刚刚提到的
these questions are meant to be open-ended
这些是开放式问题
and there isn't really a right answer to any of them.
没有什么标准答案
They're meant to give you an idea of some of the problems you
只是让你感受在现实中
might have to tackle in a real life scenario.
可能需要思考的问题